# AHMET BAHADIR COL

Software Engineer, Canada PR holder

Location: Toronto, Canada • Mobile: 437 - 463 - 0322 • Email: ahmetbahadircol@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ahmetbahadircol • Website: www.ahmetcol.com • Github: https://github.com/ahmetbahadircol

## **QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY**

Industrial Engineering graduate with 4+ years of experience in Python, Django REST, and SQL in the software engineering industry. Proficient in system design, OOP principles, and design patterns (MVC, MVVM). Extensive experience in ERP projects, database design, and optimization. Developed financial bots using Python and libraries such as Selenium, Pandas, and NumPy.

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Languages Tools

Python | Django | Git | R Language | SQL | C | HTML | GO Kubernetes | Docker | Jenkins | Jira | Confluence

Cloud Computing Services

PostgreSQL | MS SQL Server | MySQL | NoSQL

AWS (Amazon Web Services)

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Plentific, London - UK (Remote)

Backend Software Engineer II ● March 2022 - Feb 2024

- Developed and optimized RESTful API endpoints using Django REST Framework, improving response times by 20%.
- Enhanced system security with Auth0 integration for user authentication and authorization.
- Reduced production bugs by 40% through rigorous testing and debugging.
- Managed CI/CD pipelines using Kubernetes, ensuring efficient feature delivery.
- Managed Git for streamlined collaboration on projects with multiple contributors.

Atiker Software, Ankara - Turkey

ERP Project Engineer • March 2020 – March 2022

- Led ERP implementation projects, increasing client satisfaction by 15%.
- Optimized database queries by 25%, designed and developed SQL procedures to support business processes.

Turkish Aerospace Industries, Ankara - Turkey

Engineering Intern • Nov 2018 - May 2019

• Technologies and tools: Kibana, Logstash, and Elasticsearch.

MAN Truck & Buses, Ankara - Turkey

**Graduation Project Student • Aug 2018 – May 2019** 

Technologies and tools: Excel, Ms Access, MySQL and Ms Word.

### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor's in Industrial Engineering** 

Hacettepe University, Ankara - Turkey

Thesis: A Database Solution for The Cross Functional Team Allocation Problem in MAN

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Plentific Python/Django Bootcamp, 2022 BTK Academy SQL Applications, 2021